

Muhammad Hakeem Wiyar

Date of birth: 07/12/2003 | **Nationality:** Afghan | **Gender:** Male | **Phone number:**

(+93) 776992603 (Home) | Email address mrwiyarahmadzai@gmail.com

WhatsApp Messenger: +93 776992603

Address: 5th District, Qambar Square, 1010, Kabul, Afghanistan

ABOUT ME

I am Muhammad Hakeem Wiyar, a dedicated professional with a strong background in English, Computer Science, and Mathematics. My passion for Science and Technology has shaped my career. Over the past three years, I have learned at various educational centers in Kabul, developing essential skills such as communication, critical thinking, interpersonal skills, networking, and leadership, positively impacting students of different proficiency levels. My exceptional performance has earned me several awards, reflecting my contributions. My resilience and adaptability enable me to excel in diverse environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/03/2022 - 15/09/2022 Kabul, Afghanistan

ENGLISH INSTRUCTOR | VOLUNTEER AFGHAN EDUCATIONAL CENTER

Responsibilities:

- Teaching General and academic English courses.
- Creating engaging lesson plans that cover vocabulary, grammar, pronunciation, reading, writing, and speaking skills.
- Designing Activities that encourage active participation of students.
- Creating a supportive atmosphere where students feel comfortable taking risks and making mistakes.
- Regularly evaluating students' progress through assignments, quizzes, tests, and oral assessments.
- Evaluating and grading students' work, provide feedback.
- Communicating student progress to parents and participate in center-wide activities.
- Tailoring your teaching to accommodate diverse learning styles and abilities

01/07/2022 - 01/01/2023 Kabul, Afghanistan

Computer INSTRUCTOR | VOLUNTEER AFGHAN EDUCATIONAL CENTER

01/07/2022 - 01/01/2023 Kabul, Afghanistan

MATH INSTRUCTOR | VOLUNTEER AFGHAN EDUCATIONAL CENTER

Responsibilities:

- Teaching General and academic mathematics courses.
- Creating engaging lesson plans that cover every day lessons, practice, homework, student participation, problem solving, and problem-solving skills.
- Designing Activities that encourage active participation of students.
- Creating a supportive atmosphere where students feel comfortable taking risks and making mistakes.
- Regularly evaluating students' progress through assignments, quizzes, tests, and oral assessments.
- Evaluating and grading students' work, provide feedback.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2022-2023 Kabul, Afghanistan

DIGITAL LOGIC AND DESIGN PROGRAM Top in Town Technology

01/06/2024-31/12/2024 Kabul, Afghanistan

WEB DESIGN CERTIFICATE UPSKILL LEARNING CENTER

17/06/2021 Peshawar, Pakistan

Potential Teachers Training Certificate The Iqra English language and computer academy

06/09/2009 - 05/06/2021 Kabul, Afghanistan

SECONDRY EDUCATION (HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA) Hazrat Qais Bin-E-Saad High School

2019-2021 Peshawar, Pakistan

DIPLOMA IN ENGLISH LANGUAGE (DEL) THE IQRA ENGLISH LANGUAGE INSTITUTE

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s) **PASHTO** native language: **PASHTO**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
PERSIAN	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
ENGLISH	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2
URDO	C1	C1	B2	B2	C1
HINDI	C1	A1	C1	C1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Organizational and planning | various social media (including: Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, LinkedIn, Instagram) | Video Conferencing (Zoom, Teams, Skype, WebEx) - Advanced Web Technologies Fundamentals - HTML, CSS | Beginner JavaScript for Web Development | MS Office package | Adobe Photoshop (Expert) | Adobe illustrator, InDesign, Light room | Good intercultural communication | good understanding of the EU institutions

MANAGEMENT AND LEADERSHIP SKILLS

Visionary Leadership, Mentoring and Coaching, Decision-Making, Strategic Thinking, Problem-Solving. Emotional intelligence, Delegation, Team Building, Negotiation Skills, Financial Acumen

HONOURS AND AWARDS

01/06/2024 - 31/12/2024 Kabul, Afghanistan

CERTIFICATE OF APPRETIATION - UPSKILL LEARNING CENTER

I was awarded this certificate for successfully completing Front End Development at Upskill Learning center. I have learned some technologies in this center such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Tailwind, React and Figma. We have done many practical projects in all above technologies.

CERTIFICATE OF APPRETIATION - Hazrat Qais Bin Saad High School

I was provided with this certificate for my active participation in a debate competition held by Hazrat Qais Bin Saad High School.

05/06/2021 Peshawar, Pakistan

Achivement Award - Hazrat Qais Bin Saad High School

I was awarded this certificate for my attaining the first position in a book competition held by Hazrat Qais Bin Saad High School.

01/2022 Kabul, Afghanistan

CERTIFICATE OF APPRECIATION – SEDIQI LEARNING CENTER

I was rewarded this certificate for my excellent performance in Kankoor exam. I have received 320.513 numbers in our Kankor exam and I was enrolled to the faculty of computer science at Kabul Polytechnic University for this achievement the Sedigi Learning Center gave me this certificate of appreciation.

05/06/2021 Peshawar, Pakistan

CERTIFICATE OF APPRECIATION - Hazrat Qais Bin Saad High School

I was rewarded this certificate for my excellent performance in the last three years of high school because I have achieved 99.39% for my transcript and the score of my last year in high school was 99,65. My scores was best in whole school for that the school administration gave me this certificate of appreciation. I won the first place in a big meeting where all the first positioners of Peshawar were available.

06/2021 Peshawar, Pakistan

CERTIFICATE OF APPRECIATION - Hazrat Qais Bin-E-Saad High School

I was rewarded this certificate for my outstanding numbers in school competition.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Computer, Internet, Technologies, Reading, Writing, Mathematics puzzles and games, Art and design, participating in academic clubs, engaging in photography and editing, learning a new language, joining a debate club, Participating in online courses or MOOCs

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Negotiation, Team Collaboration, Open-Mindedness, Feedback Giving and Receiving, Clarity and Conciseness, Active Listening, Conflict Resolution, Cultural Awareness, Verbal Communication, Nonverbal Communication

VOLUNTEERING

01/03/2022 - 15/09//2022 Kabul, Afghanistan

ENGLISH LANGUAGE TEACHER Afghan Educational Center

I worked as a volunteer English Language teacher at Afghan Educational Center for six and half months.

RECOMMENDATIONS

Ahmad Hussain Tahirzad Headmaster						
Jabir Bin-E-Hayan Private School						
Jubil Bill E Hayall I Hvace School						
Email	Phone (+93) 785916055					
Muhammad Ayoub Salih English Teacher						

Jabir Ben-E-Hayan Private high school

Email <u>muhammadayoubsalih@gmail.corh</u> Phone (+93) 771985955